<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Talks and Events on Bob Killen</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/</link><description>Recent content in Talks and Events on Bob Killen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Peek Behind the Curtain: Managing the Kubernetes Contributor Community</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2020-03-07-a-peek-behind-the-curtain-managing-the-kubernetes-community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2020-03-07-a-peek-behind-the-curtain-managing-the-kubernetes-community/</guid><description>The Kubernetes community is a vibrant beacon in open source. It takes a village to enable a city of contributors doing what they do best. There are a lot of fun stories and lessons to be shared from helping out the community. One lesson is taken straight from the Kubernetes project itself: declarative config management. Most aspects of the community are managed using declarative configs. Adding a new SIG, GitHub org member, and even Slack channel, involves updating and PRing a change into one of the many Kubernetes repos.</description></item><item><title>Ansible, Integration Testing, and You.</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2017-07-26-ansible-integration-testing-and-you/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2017-07-26-ansible-integration-testing-and-you/</guid><description>Ansible is quickly becoming one of, if not the most prevalent Configuration Management tools. It&amp;rsquo;s rapid growth however, is not mirrored in the tooling and processes to test and validate Ansible&amp;rsquo;s roles or playbooks. Thankfully, these tools exist in other communities, and can be easily adapted. This talk covers everything needed to get started with writing, integrating and automating these tests both locally and in AWS using a suite of common frameworks borrowed from the chef community: Test-Kitchen and ServerSpec.</description></item><item><title>CNCF Research User Group KubeConEU 2020 [Event Postponed]</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2020-03-31-cncf-research-user-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2020-03-31-cncf-research-user-group/</guid><description>Interested in improving the Research experience with Kubernetes, or simply running research workloads on it? The CNCF Research User Group’s purpose is to serve as a focal point for the discussion and advancement of Research Computing using “Cloud Native” technologies. Since the group’s inception 6 months ago, key areas have been identified as gaps within the ecosystem. This session would serve as an opportunity to share with a broader audience some of the key challenges the Research-user-group has identified, and showcase project updates on key tools that the research community is developing to address these challenges.</description></item><item><title>CNCF Research User Group KubeConNA 2019</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2019-11-20-cncf-research-user-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2019-11-20-cncf-research-user-group/</guid><description>This session is open to those interested in running Kubernetes and cloud native platforms in a research context. The CNCF Research User Group’s purpose is to function as a focal point for the discussion and advancement of Research Computing using “Cloud Native” technologies. This includes enumerating current practices, identifying gaps, and directing effort to improve the Research Cloud Computing ecosystem. Mission statement: https://github.com/cncf/research-user-group</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Solutions To Run HPC Workloads</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-11-14-cloud-infrastructure-solutions-to-run-hpc-workloads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-11-14-cloud-infrastructure-solutions-to-run-hpc-workloads/</guid><description>Virtualization and containers have grown to see more prominent use within the realm of HPC. Adoption of these tools has enabled IT Organizations to reduce costs while making it easier to manage large pools of compute, storage and networking resources. However, performance overheads, networking integrations, and system complexity pose daunting architectural challenges.
OpenStack, Docker, Charliecloud, Singularity, Kubernetes, and Mesos all pose their own set of unique benefits and challenges. This Birds of a Feather is aimed at architects, administrators, software engineers, and scientists interested in designing and deploying cloud infrastructure solutions to run HPC workloads.</description></item><item><title>Federated Kubernetes - As a platform for Distributed Scientific Computing</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-03-15-federated-kubernetes-as-a-platform-for-distributed-scientific-computing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-03-15-federated-kubernetes-as-a-platform-for-distributed-scientific-computing/</guid><description>An overview of Kubernetes Federation, it&amp;rsquo;s research and scientific applications, and how the SLATE project intends to tackle them.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Kubernetes</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-05-19-getting-started-with-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-05-19-getting-started-with-kubernetes/</guid><description>The 2nd session of the Beginner Track of the Saturday Workshop. This hour and a half session serves and an introduction to Kubernetes, it&amp;rsquo;s core components, and will finish up by touching upon Workloads. This is an interactive session and attendees should come prepared with minikube installed. Attendees should come away with a good understanding of the basics and grasp next steps for continuing their Kubernetes journey.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Kubernetes Workshop (Full-Day)</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-10-15-introduction-to-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-10-15-introduction-to-kubernetes/</guid><description>Containers have shifted the way applications are packaged and delivered. Their use with cloud oriented services, data science and machine-learning is skyrocketing with the beneficial side effect of enabling reproducible research. This rise in use has necessitated the need to explore and adopt better container-centric orchestration tools. Of these tools, Kubernetes - an open-source container platform born within Google &amp;ndash; has become the de-facto standard.
Kubernetes API-driven, highly extensible design has lead to its adoption by numerous vendors and projects.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Kubernetes Workshop (Half-Day)</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-11-11-introduction-to-kubernetes-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-11-11-introduction-to-kubernetes-workshop/</guid><description>Containers have shifted the way applications are packaged and delivered. Their use in data science and machine learning is skyrocketing with the beneficial side effect of enabling reproducible research. This rise in use has necessitated the need to explore and adopt better container-centric orchestration tools. Of these tools, Kubernetes - an open-source container platform born within Google &amp;ndash; has become the de-facto standard.
Kubernetes API-driven, highly extensible design has lead to its adoption by numerous vendors and projects.</description></item><item><title>KEPs BoF: Driving enhancements for... Enhancements [Event Postponed]</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2020-03-30-keps-bof-driving-enhancements-for-enhancements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2020-03-30-keps-bof-driving-enhancements-for-enhancements/</guid><description>Kubernetes Enhancement Proposals (KEPs) have emerged as the canonical means of proposing changes to the Kubernetes project.
We&amp;rsquo;ve seen some net benefits from introducing the process, but as with anything that requires SIG Chair/Technical Lead/&amp;ldquo;top-level&amp;rdquo; approval, KEPs suffer from lack of merge velocity, due to the increased burden on reviewers.
In this Birds of a Feather session, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss a few things: - your experiences with KEPs - buffering your KEP reviewer/approver pool - techniques to defer contentious decisions (the coveted &amp;ldquo;merge early, iterate often&amp;rdquo;) - restructuring KEPs to ease reviews - KEP Book Club - the upcoming KEPs website</description></item><item><title>KubeconEU: Office Hours Live!</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-05-04-kubeconeu-office-hours-live/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-05-04-kubeconeu-office-hours-live/</guid><description>This session is a live office hours session about Kubernetes. We will have a panel of Kubernetes developers available for you to ask questions and have them answered live for the audience.
&amp;ldquo;Office Hours is a live stream where we answer live questions about Kubernetes from users on the YouTube channel. Office hours are a regularly scheduled meeting where people can bring topics to discuss with the greater community. They are great for answering questions, getting feedback on how you’re using Kubernetes, or to just passively learn by following along.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes: The New Research Platform</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2019-05-21-kubernetes-the-new-research-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2019-05-21-kubernetes-the-new-research-platform/</guid><description>Academic research institutions are at a precipice. They have historically been constrained to supporting classic “job” style workloads. With the growth of new workflow practices such as streaming data, science gateways, and more “dynamic” research using lambda-like functions, they must now support a variety of workloads.
In this talk, Lindsey and Bob will discuss some difficulties faced by academic institutions and how Kubernetes offers an extensible solution to support the future of research.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes: The Next Research Platform</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2019-03-13-kubernetes-the-next-research-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2019-03-13-kubernetes-the-next-research-platform/</guid><description>Kubernetes has become the defacto standard as a platform for container orchestration. Its ease of extending and many integrations has paved the way for a wide variety of data science and research tooling to be built on top of it.
From all encompassing tools like Kubeflow that make it easy for researchers to build end-to-end Machine Learning pipelines to specific orchestration of analytics engines such as Spark; Kubernetes has made the deployment and management of these things easy.</description></item><item><title>Managing Research Needs at the University of Michigan using Kubernetes (podcast)</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2020-02-04-managing-research-needs-at-the-university-of-michigan-using-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2020-02-04-managing-research-needs-at-the-university-of-michigan-using-kubernetes/</guid><description>Managing Research Needs at the University of Michigan using Kubernetes with Bob Killen
Keeping with our KubeCon theme, we caught up with Bob at the event to discuss how his group at UM is deploying Kubernetes. In our conversation, we explore the user experience of his broad user base, including those using KubeFlow environments, and how those users are taking advantage of distributed computing. We also discuss if ML/AI focused Kubernetes users should fear that the larger non-ML/AI user base will negatively impact their feature needs, where the largest gaps currently exist in trying to support these ML/AI users’ workloads, where Bob sees things going from a user perspective, and what are the things those users are asking about most?</description></item><item><title>Meeting HPC Container Challenges as a Community</title><link>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-11-13-meeting-hpc-container-challenges-as-a-community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrbobbytabl.es/talk/2018-11-13-meeting-hpc-container-challenges-as-a-community/</guid><description>Containers increase the likelihood users can run the latest version of HPC applications in their data center, because it&amp;rsquo;s easier for administrators to install them and developers to deploy them. But we need to build and leverage an active community to solve remaining challenges.
The BoF presents, prioritizes, and gathers further input on top issues and budding solutions around containerization of HPC applications. Lightning talks nominated in ongoing community discussions describe the community&amp;rsquo;s top issues, frame challenges, highlight progress and plans.</description></item></channel></rss>